## **DAYO AWOBEKU**

#### FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Segueda, Lagos, 100276, Nigeria

#### ABOUT ME

An ambitious problem-solving web developer with experience building user-friendly applications, with pixel-perfect design implementations using the React.js framework and Next.js framework. I ensure the writing of well-optimized and scalable code, achieving a time to interactive (TTI) of approximately 1.2seconds and application performance scores of over 80%.

### **EDUCATION**

#### BACHELOR OF SCIENCE

University of Ibadan, Ibadan

Bachelor of Science in the Department of Biomedical Laboratory Science.

### LINKS

### LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/dayoawobeku

Twitter:

https://www.twitter.com/dayoaw obeku

GitHub:

https://www.github.com/dayoaw obeku

### SKILLS

React Js

Javascript

Tailwind CSS

Bootstrap

Figma

Adobe XD

Strong design skills

Strong analytical skills

GraphQl

## WORK EXPERIENCE

FRONTEND DEVELOPER | Dojah | Lagos | Aug 2021 - Present

Worked in conjunction with a team that is building the Fastest KYC and User Onboarding Platform in Africa to help users and companies manage user identity across Africa.

Stack: JavaScript, React JS, React Testing Library, Redux, React-Query, Tailwind

- Created scalable reusable components for react client.
- Created optimized reusable custom hooks.
- Integrated API endpoints on the client application, admin dashboard, and front-facing landing page.
- Wrote unit and integration tests for components and hooks using react testing library.
- Worked on technical refinement documents for user stories.
- Collaborated with team members using the SCRUM framework.
- Created close to pixel-perfect user interfaces on the client application, admin dashboard, front-facing landing page, and widgets.
- Applied good SEO principles and ensured that the user application and landing page follow them.

# **FRONTEND DEVELOPER** | *Outlierz* | *Lagos* | *Jan 2021 - Jul 2021* **Contract**

Worked on the frontend architecture of a startup in Lagos, Nigeria, dedicated to the discovery and exposure of talented athletes emerging from Africa.

Stack: React, HTML5, CSS3

- Collaborated with web designers to talk about the layout and design of the project.
- Built the entire website from beginning to end.
- Ensured cross-platform compatibility.

## PRODUCT DESIGNER | Decasoft | Feb 2021 - Apr 2021

#### Contrac

Worked with another product designer to redesign the entire admin application for Decasoft, a company highly skilled in the business of creating internet-based applications, mobile apps, and system integration.

Stack: Figma, Notion

- Carried out extensive user research, and created wireframes and prototypes for the application.
- Created high-fidelity mockups for the application.
- Collaborated with developers and the company's representative to ensure the finished product aligned with the company's goals.

# FRONTEND DEVELOPER | Wedding Planer | Lagos | Nov 2020 - Dec 2020 Contract

Worked on the frontend architecture of a wedding planner landing page in Lagos, Nigeria, a website for intending couples to plan their ceremony with the help of a professional.

Stack: React, HTML5, CSS3

- Collaborated with web designers to talk about the layout and design of the project.
- $\bullet\,$  Built the entire website from beginning to end.
- Ensured cross-platform compatibility.

## PROJECTS

# **DO DEEL** | *Lagos*A Mobile Application for digital onboarding CDS (Community Development

Service) in Nigeria that automates the total user experience from registration to completion during his/her service year as a digital onboader.

- Link: https://www.dodeelcds.com.ng
- Position: Product designer, Frontend Developer
  Technology Used: React, Redux, Firebase, Figma
- Features: Registration system, attendance system, real-time chat system, business onboarding

# INTERNSHIP

FRONTEND DEVELOPER | Zuri Team | Lagos | Feb 2021 - Jun 2021 Worked with a team of about 20 individuals to build an Escrow platform that serves as a third party between buyers and sellers for B2C companies.

Stack: React JS, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Figma

- Designed usable and visually-appealing user interfaces with Figma.
- Built the user interfaces to be as close to pixel-perfection and responsive on all screen sizes.
- Created scalable reusable components for future use.
- Integrated API endpoints on the user dashboard.
- Optimized components for optimum performance.